Rudger Gravestein

Self-employed Consultant, Architect, Developer (Magento EE/CE) at Triple-networks rud5gmobile@gmail.com

Summary

Currently self-employed, so you might be able to hire me. Just send me a pm. ---- Experienced PHP software engineer, experienced in developing Magento Enterprise, Magento CE from start till deployment, knowledge of Zend Framework, OOP design patterns, databases MySQL/SQL, used to work in a self-organizing, crossfunctional team with good knowledge and use of SCM (Software configuration management) to track and understand changes. Experience with software development lifecycle, from design and implementation to unit testing and production deployment. Experience with working and administering *nix systems. Achievements * Responsible Magento Enterpise project for multinational. * Setup multiple Magento projects as teamlead. * Automated all deployment projects * Setup of revision control system (subversion) for all existing and new projects in a company, including basic build-scripts for deploying to multiple servers. * Setup of Trac/Jira/Fisheye for revision control management. * Upgraded existing PHP4 projects to new PHP5 server. * Grow on the Company website from 50 Unique Visitors per month to 20.000 Unique Visitors per month within 3 years. * Created complete backend for all data managing related operations in a media company, including ftp, upload, download, soap connection with partners and metadata library. Specialties: PHP5, MySQL, SVN, Server architecture, Scrum / Agile, xHTML, CSS.

Experience

Independent Consultant & Developer (Magento Certified) at Triple-networks

July 2015 - Present (5 months)

Automation is key. So in short: I love Chef, devops, CI, AWS, Virtual machines (and containers), Magento Enterprise & ZendFramework. Info about Chef: https://www.chef.io/ Info about Magento Certified Developer Plus: http://magento.com/training/catalog/certified-developer-and-developer-plus

System Architect Magento Enterprise at Youwe Commerce BV

September 2014 - July 2015 (11 months)

Responsible for setup architecture and capturing the requirements of international Magento Enterprise projects.

Senior Software Engineer at Youwe / Drecomm

January 2012 - July 2015 (3 years 7 months)

Owner at Triple-networks

October 2005 - July 2015 (9 years 10 months)

Technical Team Lead - Magento at Youwe

February 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 8 months)

Senior Software Engineer at Solware BV

September 2009 - December 2011 (2 years 4 months)

CTO at Triple Vision Record Distribution BV

October 2005 - August 2009 (3 years 11 months)

Developing a technology vision for TripleVision, strategic consulting, web site UI (front & backend), web site traffic growth. My job is to worry about technical issues now and in the future.

Software Engineer at Coolblue

September 2005 - 2006 (1 year)

http://webwereld.nl/e-commerce/28264-webwinkels-diregt-over-naar-coolblue

Lead programmer / Webdeveloper at Direqt

2004 - September 2005 (1 year)

Programmer at Infopact Netwerkdiensten

1999 - 2001 (2 years)

Projects

winkelstraat.nl

May 2012 to December 2012

Members:Rudger Gravestein, Brennon Blokland, Daniel Sloof

Agile project Magento Enterprise

MusicVI

September 2013 to Present

Members:Rudger Gravestein, Anton Naruta, Timo van der Heiden, Stefan Blokker

An online platform for producers and musicians.

Klöckner co multi metal distribution eCommerce

October 2013 to Present

Members:Rudger Gravestein, Rob Wiek, Pascal Brouwers, Mike Bijnsdorp, Laurentius Judhianto, Bas Ouwehand, Bogdan Lewinsky, Monique Febus, Brennon Blokland, Jasper Goertz

Agile project Magento Enterprise http://webshop.ods-assortiment.nl/

Totalsports.nl

January 2014 to Present

Members: Rudger Gravestein, Bogdan Lewinsky, Mike Bijnsdorp

Magento project http://www.totalsports.nl/

Beetshop.NL

January 2012 to Present

Members: Rudger Gravestein, Brennon Blokland

Development Magento Community webshop http://www.beetshop.nl/

MTBGigant.NL

January 2013 to Present

Members:Rudger Gravestein, Omar Ras

Development on mtbgigant.nl project: Magento Community Edition http://www.mtbgigant.nl/

Post.NL

January 2013 to Present

Members:Rudger Gravestein, Daniel Sloof

Development on the post.nl Magento Enterprise Edition http://www.postnl.nl/

setup autovoordeelshop.nl in the cloud

September 2014 to Present

Members:Rudger Gravestein, Ilse Louter

Setup Chef for autovoordeelshop for automated deployment in the rackspace cloud.

Certifications

Magento Certified Developer Plus

Prometric License wbedus5363 December 2012

Zend Certified Engineer

Zend License ZEND013253 March 2010

Zend Framework Certified Engineer

Zend License ZEND013253 December 2010

Skills & Expertise

MySQL

PHP

Continuous Integration

Scrum

Zend Framework

Magento

Git

OOP

Agile Methodologies

Design Patterns

System Administration

Web Development

Software Engineering

PHPUnit

Apache

jQuery

JIRA

Linux

Bash		
CSS		
XML		
Open Source		
AJAX		
HTML		
Ubuntu		
Github		
HTML 5		
BDD		
Chef		
Ruby		
DevOps		
TDD		
phpspec		
Berkshelf		
Databases		
JSON		
Courses		
Senior Software Engineer		
Solware BV		
Scrum for Team Members		
Zend PHP5.2 Certification		
Zend Framework Certification		
Languages		
Dutch	(Native or bilingual proficiency)	
English	(Full professional proficiency)	
	(1 un professional proficiency)	
Education		
Hogeschool Rotterdam		
HIO, Software Development, 1998 - 2004		

Interests

music, software, hardware & running.

Rudger Gravestein

Self-employed Consultant, Architect, Developer (Magento EE/CE) at Triple-networks rud5gmobile@gmail.com



3 people have recommended Rudger

"Already charmed by Rudger's attitude in our first interview, I knew he would be a great colleague to join the team. He showed a proactive and enthusiastic character combined with a high level of expertise and eagerness to keep on learning."

— Sohrab Hosseini, managed Rudger at Youwe / Drecomm

11 11

— Petra Visbeen, was Rudger's client

"Rudger is a talented programmer and a fun person to work with! With his excellent skills in PHP he's up for any job. He can singlehandedly complete challenging projects and often comes up with extremely creative solutions. I enjoyed working with him a lot! And besides all that, he's also a great DJ...;)"

— Joost Nauta, managed Rudger at Direqt

Contact Rudger on LinkedIn